<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<content><string id="body">As Season 2 of Heroes of the Interstellar Armed Forces comes to an end, we are changing the competition from quarterly to monthly. We've also got a wide assortment of bugfixes and a few new VScript functions.

[h1]Campaigns[/h1]
[list]
[*][b]Jacob's Rest: Rydberg Reactor:[/b] Fixed a bug in the ending area where marines could jump with jump jets underground to their death.
[*][b]Area 9800: Power Plant's Generator:[/b] Fixed narrow catwalks negatively affecting AI pathing.
[*][b]Operation Cleansweep: Landing Bay 7:[/b] Removed an invisible ceiling near the south egg room to prevent unintuitive grenade trajectories.
[*][b]Operation Cleansweep: U.S.C. Medusa:[/b] Pods will now reopen if a marine leaves, rather than if they are fully empty.
[*][b]Research 7: Illyn Forest:[/b] Fixed generator being targetable by marine bots.
[*][b]Tears for Tarnor: Oasis Colony Spaceport:[/b] Fixed a soft lock if a boomer used in a cinematic is killed early due to a challenge.
[*][b]Tilarus-5: SynTek Hospital:[/b] Reworked countdown at end of mission.
[*][b]Lana's Escape: Lana's Bridge:[/b] Fixed escape objective not updating when a marine dies.
[*][b]Lana's Escape: Lana's Sewer:[/b] Fixed escape objective not updating when a marine dies.
[*][b]Lana's Escape: Lana's Complex:[/b] Expanded the evacuation zone.
[*][b]Paranoia: Crucial Point:[/b] Reworked the final encounter. Marines must now defend a generator. If the generator is damaged, it will stop the completion progress until fixed by a tech. If no marine is near the generator, it will take additional damage.
[*][b]Nam Humanum: Logistics Area:[/b] Reworked geometry near a fire.
[*][b]Nam Humanum: Groundwork Labs:[/b] Fixed a large door being able to be damaged, which would cause it to get stuck.
[*][b]BioGen Corporation: Invisible Threat:[/b] Added markers and a visual clue for the fan room to make it easier to navigate for players who do not know the way.
[*][b]Bonus Mission 7:[/b] Fixed narrow catwalks negatively affecting AI pathing.
[/list]

[h1]Aliens[/h1]
[list]
[*]Added Queen sound effects from the City 17 campaign.
[/list]

[h1]Weapons[/h1]
[list]
[*]Fixed piercing chance calculation for bullets that went through a door or other non-living object. (A 200% chance, 290% chance, and 300% chance now all become 100% chance of piercing another target rather than 0%, 90%, and 0%.)
[*][b]M868 Flamer Unit:[/b] Doubled ammo per clip and ammo usage. Primary attack now uses one unit of fuel per shot.
[*][b]IAF Minigun:[/b] Doubled ammo per clip and ammo usage. Primary attack now uses one unit of ammo per shot.
[/list]

[h1]Translations[/h1]
[list]
[*]Updated Chinese translation.
[*]Updated German translation.
[*]Updated Italian translation.
[*]Updated Japanese translation.
[*]Updated Russian translation.
[/list]

[h1]Misc[/h1]
[list]
[*]Fixed non-Workshop addons acting as if they were disabled in the mission chooser.
[*]Fixed a crash at startup if the PATH environment variable was very long.
[*]Added an advanced setting to reduce motion on menus.
[*]Improved keyboard/controller navigation on Advanced Settings and Game Settings.
[*]Added a warning on the lobby list if you have a different version of a map than the host.
[*]prop_dynamic now uses server-driven animation timing. This fixes vault door opening animations getting desynchronized, but increases network bandwidth requirements in missions that use a lot of animated props.
[/list]

[h1]Mapping[/h1]
[list]
[*]Fixed npc_bullseye failing to compile due to a key being too long.
[*]npc_bullseye now inherits AI relationships from its faction and is not an enemy of all by default.
[*]ai_relationship now delays applying its effect to gameplay start rather than map spawn.
[/list]

[h1]VScript[/h1]
[list]
[*]Added new VScript class TempEnts which allows creating Temporary Entities on clients.
[*]Added new global VScript functions to use when creating Temporary Entities.
[*]Added the PlayerVoiceListener class to VScript with access to the following functions.
[*]Added new VScript functions for CASW_Player.
[/list]

[h2]TempEnts[/h2]

[code]void Create( CBasePlayer player, string name, float delay, table )[/code]
Queue a temp entity for transmission on a client from a passed table of SendProp data.
Passing null for a player will playback Temp Entity on all clients.

[code]void GetPropTypes( string name, table )[/code]
Fills in a passed table with all SendProps and their types for the temp entity

[code]void GetNames( table )[/code]
Fills in a passed table with the names of all temp entities

[h2]PlayerVoiceListener[/h2]

[code]bool IsPlayerSpeaking( int nPlayerIndex )[/code]
Returns whether the player specified is speaking.

[code]float GetPlayerSpeechDuration( int nPlayerIndex )[/code]
Returns the number of seconds the player has been continuously speaking.

[h2]Global[/h2]

[code]int PrecacheParticleSystem( string name )[/code]
Precaches a particle material

[code]int GetParticleSystemIndex( string name )[/code]
Converts a previously precached material into an index

[code]string GetParticleSystemNameFromIndex( int index )[/code]
Converts a previously precached material index into a string

[code]void PrecacheEffect( string name )[/code]
Precaches an effect

[code]int GetEffectIndex( const char *name )[/code]
Converts a previously precached effect into an index

[code]string GetEffectNameFromIndex( int index )[/code]
Converts a previously precached effect index into a string

[code]int GetDecalIndexForName( string name )[/code]
Get decal index from a string

[h2]CASW_Player[/h2]

[code]CBaseEntity GetNPC()[/code]
Returns entity the player is inhabiting

[code]CBaseEntity GetSpectatingNPC()[/code]
Returns entity the player is spectating

[code]CBaseEntity GetViewNPC()[/code]
Returns entity the player is spectating, else will return inhabiting entity

[code]CASW_Marine GetMarine()[/code]
Returns the marine the player is commanding

[code]CBaseEntity FindPickerEntity()[/code]
Finds the nearest entity in front of the player

[code]Vector GetCrosshairTracePos()[/code]
Returns the world location directly beneath the player's crosshair</string><string id="subtitle"></string><string id="summary"></string><string id="title">Alien Swarm: Reactive Drop Update - September 3, 2022</string></content>