<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<content><string id="body">Here are some fixes for recently-reported bugs and a few map and workshop improvements.

[list]
[*][b]IAF HAS42 Devastator:[/b] Increased firing sound volume for the player firing the weapon.
[*]Fixed end-of-mission stat graph lines being unexpectedly far apart in some cases. (Thanks SJAS)
[*]Updated how the Mission Complete screen is rendered to allow supporting more languages.
[*]Addons with an autoexec file are now listed on the workshop under the "Config" tag.
[*]Going forward, uploading addons with config files in them to the workshop will be limited to autoexec_[addon ID].cfg to avoid collisions between different addons and between addons and user files.
[*]Fixed an issue that caused the "help" command to limit descriptions to 80 characters. (Thanks 法克*尤尔*马泽尔 and Zero)
[*]Fixed Bastille only playing one of his two death sounds. (Thanks Beka and krtek2k)
[*]Fixed a bug where sv_memlimit would sometimes fail to exit. (Thanks Mithrand)
[*]Fixed the asw_jeep entity being unintentionally disabled. (Thanks jhheight)
[/list]

[h2]Tears for Tarnor: Insertion Point[/h2]
[list]
[*]Changed how some invisible walls are defined to allow drones to jump over certain rocks but not through cave walls.
[*]Increased the height of some invisible walls intended to keep players from being thrown out of the playable space by shieldbugs. (Thanks kubaaa015)
[*]Reduced lighting complexity for areas far from the playable space.
[/list]

[h2]Accident 32: Lab Ruins[/h2]
[list]
[*]Changed some materials in the starting area.
[*]Fixed being able to hear the boss doors closing when the mission starts.
[*]The sewer now deals damage over time instead of killing instantly.
[*]Added ladders to allow climbing out of the sewer.
[*]Added stairs to the area where the harvester spawns in the beginning.
[*]Added an area to the west of the big bridge with additional supplies.
[*]An ammo stash on the main path has been reduced from 100% full to 60% full to encourage seeking optional supply areas.
[/list]</string><string id="subtitle"></string><string id="summary"></string><string id="title">Alien Swarm: Reactive Drop Update - September 18, 2023</string></content>