<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<content><string id="body">Today, Alien Swarm: Reactive Drop celebrates 6 years on Steam. You'll earn [url=https://store.steampowered.com/news/app/563560/view/3267945303130139335]double experience points all week[/url], but we know what you're really here for. Let's unwrap some presents:

[h1]New Campaign: Accident 32[/h1]

Mysterious, seemingly harmless green glowing gems are discovered under the ground of a populated area due to abnormal radioactivity levels. The company "AMBER" came to study this supernatural material. Findings are frightening and undocumented, kept away from the public. Gems are identified to be extremely dangerous, extraterrestrial materials comprised of mostly muons. Emitted radiation modifies all biological structures in a big vicinity.

Originally released in May of 2020 and May of 2022 on the Steam Workshop, Accident 32 is a six-mission campaign which combines two three-mission campaigns into one. Marines are set out to explore the mysterious complex and headquarters of the company called "AMBER" and face a lot of threats. A bonus "AMBER Complex" mission is included which is the first three missions combined into one.

[h1]New Campaign: Adanaxis[/h1]

TODO

[h1]Collections: Weapons, Equipment, and Swarmopedia[/h1]

TODO

[h1]Mapping Competition 2023: "Boss Fight"[/h1]

This year, we're hosting our first annual community mapping competition, and what better place to start than at the end? The theme for this year is [b]Boss Fight[/b].

Create a mission or short campaign that contains a boss fight - a scripted encounter with some big bad that the marines must overcome. Will the boss be an alien, a group of aliens, or something completely new? Where will the mission take place? Why are the marines there? All of these questions and more are things you'll have to consider in the coming months.

Or, if you have a better idea, go ahead and make that instead! AS:RD mapping competition themes are optional.

Entries must be tagged with [b]BossFight2023[/b]. Competition starts today and ends August 1st. Prizes include unique ingame medals. If you need help getting started, check out the [url=https://steamcommunity.com/app/563560/discussions/1/]Modding / Mapping Help and Tips[/url] forum.

[h1]In Case You Missed It[/h1]

Here are some highlights from updates since the previous anniversary:
[list]
[*]Workshop addons can now contain videos, and missions can define their own briefing background video, or even show part of the world as the background during briefing.
[*]We're Steam Deck verified! The game runs great on the Steam Deck, and players on Linux or who use a controller have also seen improvements.
[*]There are now medals you can earn by helping with the game's development, contributing to the Steam community hub, or participating in a season of Heroes of the Interstellar Armed Forces.
[*]The slow-opening vault doors used in many missions now have more accurate collision data, allowing you to step or shoot through a partially-opened door.
[*]The all-new mission selection screen includes support for bonus missions and new "endless" missions.
[*]We've added an advanced settings menu and an advanced audio settings menu.
[*]Restarting a mission no longer requires a loading screen.
[/list]

[h1]Other changes in this update[/h1]

[h2]Campaigns[/h2]
[list]
[*][b]Area 9800: Wastelands:[/b] Fixed a harvester getting stuck in the exit during the finale gauntlet introduction scene.
[*][b]Tilarus-5: Arctic Infiltration:[/b] Fixed uber drones appearing and disappearing shortly after the start of the mission.
[*][b]Tilarus-5: SynTek Hospital:[/b] Made alarm sounds louder.
[*][b]Paranoia: Unexpected Encounter:[/b] Fixed bugs related to grenade launcher aiming.
[*][b]Paranoia: Hostile Places:[/b] Fixed bugs related to grenade launcher aiming.
[*][b]Bunker:[/b] Removed collision from an invisible ceiling beam.
[/list]

[h2]Weapons[/h2]
[list]
[*][b]ML30 Laser Trip Mine:[/b] Improved network prediction for throwing animation.
[*]Fixed the scanning animation for sentries desynchronizing from the gun's idle angle.
[*]Fixed inconsistencies in collision-checking code, most notably related to bot marines and projectiles.
[/list]

[h2]Misc[/h2]
[list]
[*]The buildcubemaps command now requires sv_cheats to be enabled.
[*]Fixed a crash when an alien tried to throw a physics object at a target who had died.
[*]Fixed a crash when leaving a screen with a dropdown menu open.
[*]Fixed the game instructor recommending marines to weld a door that is already damaged to the point where it cannot open or close.
[*]Fixed the white rounded square door used in some custom maps visually falling in the wrong direction sometimes.
[*]Fixed marines being unselected in the lobby when restarting a bonus mission that was started via a vote.
[*]The chat panel can now be opened in singleplayer (for use in custom challenges).
[/list]

[h2]Mapping[/h2]
[list]
[*]Added npc_crow, npc_pigeon, and npc_seagull.
[*]asw_env_shake can now be flagged to bypass user settings (a new convar has been added for disabling [i]all[/i] shakes regardless of this flag).
[*]Added env_headcrabcanister.
[*]Added script_intro.
[*]A new material proxy, LanguagePreference, can be used to change a texture based on the viewer's language preference. For example:[code]UnlitGeneric {
    $basetexture "example/translated_texture_english"

    Proxies {
        LanguagePreference {
            default "example/translated_texture_english"
            schinese "example/translated_texture_schinese"
            french "example/translated_texture_french"
            resultvar "$basetexture"
        }
    }
}[/code]
[/list]

[h2]VScript[/h2]
[list]
[*]Added a new method to marines: SetMarineRolls, which allows maps and challenges to change whether individual marines can jump.
[/list]</string><string id="subtitle">It's Alien Swarm: Reactive Drop's Birthday!</string><string id="summary">Today, Alien Swarm: Reactive Drop celebrates 6 years on Steam! Here's a week of double experience, two new campaigns, and some other goodies to celebrate.</string><string id="title">Alien Swarm: Reactive Drop Update - April 20, 2023</string></content>