<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<content><string id="body">We've extended the deadline for submissions to the 2024 mapping competition until the end of July, so you have two extra months to make your mission.

An update has been released with the following changes:

[h2]Balance[/h2]
[list]
[*]Reduced the attack speed of drones that are on fire by 40%. (Or 28.6%, depending on how you do the math. It now matches their normal attack speed.)
[*]Retrying the first mission of a campaign now resets eligibility for Outstanding Execution achievements.
[/list]

[h2]Heroes of the Interstellar Armed Forces[/h2]
[list]
[*]Added the [url=https://steamcommunity.com/sharedfiles/filedetails/?id=3142399089]Magnum Opus[/url] campaign by vq.
[*]Added the [url=https://steamcommunity.com/sharedfiles/filedetails/?id=3247801260]Downed Station[/url] bonus mission by legomanas.
[*]Added the [url=https://steamcommunity.com/sharedfiles/filedetails/?id=3236503229]ASBI Veteran[/url] challenge and its variants by ModdedMarionette.
[*]Removed the Absolute Madness campaign.
[*]A full list of changes to Heroes of the Interstellar Armed Forces can be found [url=https://developer.reactivedrop.com/hoiaf.html#june-1-2024-season-24]on the developer website[/url].
[/list]

[h2]Menus[/h2]
[list]
[*]Valve has added a patch to Proton Experimental that greatly improves text legibility on Linux devices like the Steam Deck.
[*]Added an alternate icon for dedicated servers known to be running a unofficial server code in the lobby list.
[*]Fixed special event timers not appearing on the main menu.
[*]Fixed certain buttons incorrectly showing a hint to use the B button on a controller when not connected to a lobby.
[*]Added an inventory tab for non-medals. Perhaps something you can find on the beta branch?
[*]Inventory items that automatically stack now show a quantity in the inventory screen.
[*]Added an icon for campaigns and missions downloaded from the Steam Workshop in the mission chooser.
[*]Fixed the Workshop publishing interface not allowing edits if the preview image has not loaded.
[*]Increased the size of tooltips for better readability.
[*]Changed the "dim" text color in the legacy server browser from black to light gray for readability.
[*]Fixed opening notifications while not on the main menu resulting in stacking menu items.
[/list]

[h2]In-Game[/h2]
[list]
[*]Fixed Swarmopedia article unlocks showing garbled text.
[*]Fixed a crash that could occur when restarting a mission while viewing a computer screen in-game.
[*]Fixed the formatting of the player voting panel when more than 8 players are in a lobby.
[*]Added the speedrun time to mission briefing.
[*]Improved formatting of dynamic objective names like "Destroy Swarm Eggs".
[*]"Download data" objectives now show a completion percentage.
[*]Fixed zombies splitting in half from sources of damage that do not have associated ammo types.
[/list]

[h2]Modding[/h2]
[list]
[*]asw_objective_triggered now has support for percentage-based formatting of objective progress.
[*]Changing rd_override_alien_selection_challenge no longer writes a message to chat.
[*]Fixed missions with no version number defined not being able to be played in multiplayer lobbies.
[/list]
</string><string id="subtitle"></string><string id="summary"></string><string id="title">Alien Swarm: Reactive Drop Update - June 1, 2024</string></content>
