<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<content><string id="body">今月のアップデートには[url=https://store.steampowered.com/news/app/563560/view/3994197038602903068]Interstellar Armed Forcesの英雄たちに関する大きな変更[/url]が含まれている他、感染デスマッチモードのバランス変更やその他様々な修正がされています。

		[h2]A note on Lag Compensation[/h2]
		The internet doesn't transmit information instantly. Information can only travel at the speed of light, and sometimes the speed of light is just too slow. For example, if a player from Frankfurt joins a lobby hosted in Beijing, even if their computers were directly connected by a very long wire, information would take 50 milliseconds to get from Frankfurt to Beijing and back. In reality, the information needs to travel much further than the 15500 km round trip because the information doesn't move in a straight line.

		When you fire a bullet, the information travels a long distance through complicated circuits before it even leaves your computer, and then it spends time traveling through a series of other computers before it finally reaches the one hosting the lobby. But that's not the end of the journey. Once the lobby host has figured out what your bullet did, that information needs to travel back to you and every other player in your lobby. By the time your bullet reaches the lobby host, the alien you were shooting might have moved! But game engines have a few tricks up their sleeves to hide this from you, and because they can't shorten the physical distance the information needs to travel, they do something easier: time travel!

		The information about the bullet you fired doesn't wait until it gets to the host and back before it shows something on your screen. First, the game running on your computer pretends the information about the bullet made a round trip to the host instantly. This is called "prediction" because the game "predicts" what the host will say happened. Prediction is shown in red in the images below.

		Second, when the information about the bullet reaches the host, the characters in the game [b]move back in time[/b] to check where your bullet would have hit. This is called "lag compensation", and is shown in blue in the images below.

[img]{STEAM_CLAN_IMAGE}/27357479/425a4e8d4330cc9628e3e924dfab3cab575580ae.png[/img]
		[i]Alien Swarm and Alien Swarm: Reactive Drop (prior to this update) lag compensation algorithm, shown with 300ms simulated round trip ping and default settings.[/i]

		That's not good! If the drone hadn't been moving toward Vegas, he would have completely missed the shot! The lobby host rewound time, but it didn't do a very good job.

		Here's what that shot will look like after this update:

[img]{STEAM_CLAN_IMAGE}/27357479/c7440efa1232f45764d0970537c88ac1f7cf9e63.png[/img]
		[i]Alien Swarm: Reactive Drop (as of this update) lag compensation algorithm, shown with 300ms simulated round trip ping and default settings.[/i]

		Much better! If you have a configuration that sets cl_lagcompensation 0, we recommend removing that command as it means the lobby host won't time travel at all when you fire a bullet. [i]The hotfix a week ago inadvertently marked cl_lagcompensation as a cheat; it can now be changed freely when not connected to a lobby.[/i]

		Want to try it out for yourself? Use the newly-added [b]sv_showimpacts 1[/b] command.

[h2]ミッション[/h2]
[list]
[*][b]Tears for Tarnor: Oasis Colony Spaceport:[/b] 警備室と金属探知ゲートの近くの天井の一部にグレネードとの接触判定があったのを修正。
[*][b]Tears for Tarnor: Oasis Colony Spaceport:[/b] 格納庫と荷物受取所の間の天井が早めに見えなくなるようにして、邪魔になりにくくした。
[*]ワークショップのミッションThe Gauntlet: Arcticで音声が鳴らなくなる問題を修正。
[/list]

[h2]武器[/h2]
[list]
[*]リロードモーション開始から短時間エイムがずれる問題があったのを修正。このせいで高精度レールライフルでファストリロードを成功させた直後などに攻撃が外れることがあった。
[*]アンロックした武器に表示される"New!"の文字が、他の武器をアンロックしてゲームを再起動すると、その武器を一度も選択した事が無いのに消えてしまう問題を修正。
[/list]

[h2]ロビー[/h2]
[list]
[*]ロビーリーダーの変更とプレイヤー追放の投票はミッションのやり直し時にリセットされなくなった。
[*]ミッションのやり直しは3秒以内(asw_instant_restart_cooldownで指定)に連続ではできなくなった。ミッション完了や失敗の画面に入ってからのやり直しには適用されない。
[*]ロビー作成画面でチャレンジ選択メニューを開いた直後に閉じると、チャレンジが"cmd_change_challenge"に変更されたように見えてしまうバグを修正。
[/list]

[h2]その他[/h2]
[list]
[*]メインメニューに通知リストとそのフィルター設定を追加。
[*]ゲーム内のインベントリアイテムの説明欄を斜体文字に対応させた。
[*]コンソール変数rd_vindicator_fire_rateを追加。0の場合、ショットガンの連射速度を継承する昔の挙動になる。
[*]メディックがホイールメニューから「ヒューッ！」のエモートを使用すると、25分の1の確率で治療装備が尽きたと叫ぶことがあったのを修正。
[*]ミッション終了時に統計情報が記録されるタイミングで、ベータ実装のクラフト素材に関するクラッシュが稀に発生していたのを修正。
[/list]]

[h2]感染デスマッチ[/h2]
[list]
[*]ライフルグレネードのダメージボーナスはノックバック威力の計算の後で計算されるようになった。
[*]ライフルグレネードのダメージを減少。
[*]ロケットのノックバック威力を大幅に増加。
[*]ロケットのダメージを増加。
[*]準備時間に受けたダメージは即座に回復するようになった。
[*]人間がゾンビに与える燃焼ダメージは焼夷地雷によるものかどうかに関わらずダメージボーナスを得られるようになった。
[*]設置されたセントリーガンは即座に消えるようになった。
[*]ロビーリーダーだけではなくサーバーコンソールとチャレンジスクリプトから、通常のデスマッチモード用のコンソールコマンドを使えるようになった。
[/list]</string><string id="subtitle"></string><string id="summary"></string><string id="title">Alien Swarm: Reactive Dropアップデート - 2024年2月1日</string></content>