<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<content><string id="body">[h2]Mapping Competition 2024 Winner[/h2]
Downed Station by legomanas
[img]{STEAM_CLAN_IMAGE}/27357479/96f9509932b257ed89058f3bcb4450083fe834de.png[/img]

[h2]Changes in this update[/h2]
[list]
[*]Removed the cl_interp convar. The game will now act as if it was set to 0.
[*]Improved the error message that is shown when attempting to connect to a server that hasn't updated yet.
[*]Fixed a particle related crash due to the "emit noise" operator being broken in this engine build.
[*]Fixed a possible crash when navigating the controls menu using a keyboard.
[*]The sound for a marine being burned but not ignited now plays for other players as well.
[*]Slightly increased how lenient the friendly fire ignite timing is when hardcore friendly fire is disabled.
[*]Fixed a case where TF2 workshop item icons could appear in the challenge selection screen for manually installed challenges.
[*]Added an AddTime input for countdown objectives.
[*]Fixed a crash when standing near a strange weapon dropped by a disconnected player.
[*]Added support for guns having a separate laserpointer attachment from their muzzle attachment.
[*]Moved camera-related convars to the server to make them available to challenges.
[*]Fixed some small text being displayed in Times New Roman on Linux.
[/list]

[h2]The IAF needs you[url=https://stats.reactivedrop.com/7a]![/url][/h2]
Alien Swarm: Reactive Drop will always be free, but that doesn't mean it doesn't take a lot of work from a lot of talented volunteers to make. If you can, consider making content for the [url=https://steamcommunity.com/app/563560/workshop/]Steam Workshop[/url], reporting bugs, proposing [url=https://github.com/ReactiveDrop/reactivedrop_public_src]code[/url] improvements, [url=https://github.com/ReactiveDrop/reactivedrop_translations]translating[/url] the game into your language, or [url=https://store.steampowered.com/itemstore/563560/]sending a dollar[/url] to one of the people who Alien Swarm: Reactive Drop possible. The IAF thanks you for your continued service, Commander.</string><string id="subtitle"></string><string id="summary"></string><string id="title">AS:RD Update - September 1, 2024 "Time's Down"</string></content>