<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<content><string id="body">Happy new year! This month's update contains fixes for controller issues, updates to the Infection deathmatch challenge, and a few miscellaneous fixes and new features.

[h2]Official Missions[/h2]
[list]
[*][b]BioGen Corporation: Operation X5:[/b] Fixed a door that was inadvertently classified as a ladder.
[*][b]BioGen Corporation: Invisible Threat:[/b] Fixed speedrun time being incorrectly calculated.
[/list]

[h2]Controller[/h2]
[list]
[*]Fixed doubled cursor movement inputs on in-game menus such as computer hacks and the briefing lobby.
[*]Fixed extra inputs being generated when switching action set. This was causing the Override command to close and re-open the hack.
[*]Fixed an issue where after starting the game with Steam in Big Picture mode or using the controller, selecting a marine with the mouse would always select Sarge.
[*]Added convars rd_input_controller_mode_mouse and rd_input_controller_mode_keyboard to lock the input mode to not-controller (0) or controller (1).
[/list]

[h2]Menus[/h2]
[list]
[*]Fixed non-English letters not being enterable into the lobby name field.
[*]Fixed 7.1 surround sound missing from 2010 audio settings menu.
[*]Fixed incorrect name for Order Specific Marine in the 2010 keyboard settings menu.
[*]Fixed download campaign button being obscured by the filters button.
[*]Fixed memory leak related to player avatars. This could sometimes lead to a "CUtlRBTree overflow" crash.
[/list]

[h2]Infection Deathmatch Challenge[/h2]
[list]
[*]Reduced the amount of bonus maximum health that comes with Last Stand.
[*]Reduced the DPS of the chainsaw when using Last Stand.
[*]Slightly increased the DPS of the chainsaw when not using Last Stand.
[*]Freeze Grenades can no longer be used. (They were already unselectable.)
[*]Significantly increased Trip Mine damage against zombies.
[*]Significantly increased Gas Grenade damage against zombies.
[*]Significantly increased Incendiary Mine damage against zombies.
[*]Electro-stunned zombies now take double damage.
[*]Medic zombies now begin regenerating health sooner after taking damage.
[*]Fixed players falling through terrain when turning into a zombie.
[*]Updated custom edits for dm_deima.
[*]Added Classic variant:[list]
[*]Last Stand mode is disabled.
[*]Prime Zombies no longer have shields.[/list]
[*]Improved bot marine pathfinding across all deathmatch game modes.
[*]Fixed sometimes seeing glows for weapons or ammo that have despawned.
[/list]

[h2]Scripting[/h2]
[list]
[*]Added a new method to rd_hud_vscript: PaintPolygon(vertices, red, green, blue, alpha, texture). vertices is an array of tables, each containing x, y, s, and t coordinates. There must be at least three vertices and they should form a convex shape in clockwise order. x and y are screen coordinates. s and t are texture coordinates, from 0 to 1.
[/list]
</string><string id="subtitle"></string><string id="summary"></string><string id="title">Alien Swarm: Reactive Drop Update - January 1, 2024</string></content>